Contact

vevely@att.net

www.linkedin.com/in/natalie-wilson-19000b3a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Healthcare Medicare

Certifications

Certified Case Manager

Natalie Wilson

Interim CNO at Hospital

Greater Chicago Area

Summary

Experienced Director Of Case Management with a demonstrated history of working in the insurance industry. Skilled in Disease Management, Microsoft Word, U.S. Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA), Team Building, and Managed Care. Strong healthcare services professional with a Master of Business Administration (MBA) focused in Applied Management and Health Care Management from Indiana Wesleyan University.

Experience

Hospital Interim CNO February 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Acute Care
Director Of Case Management
November 2017 - Present (2 years 9 months)
Acute Care

Acute Care Organization
Director of Case Management
December 2016 - October 2017 (11 months)

Cigna-HealthSpring
Director Of Health Services
March 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 7 months)
Serving 34 counties

BCBS

Senior Manager - Government Programs/ Medicare/Clinical Operations January 2014 - March 2015 (1 year 3 months)

•Responsible for developing and implementing Managed Care programs and strategies for Government Programs Clinical Operations; establishing

cost-containment goals and objectives for the department along with policies, practices and procedures needed to meet those objectives; and for representing the company and division before outside customers and consultants

- Quality Initiatives Project
- •Areas of responsibility include STARS/HEIDIS Project, Quality Initiatives
 Project. Hiring, training and mentoring, team goal management, performance
 management, professional development, diversity, and change management
- •Supervise case managers, disease managers, and member care coordinators
- •Back up for Utilization Review and DSNP (Dual Special Needs Program)
- •Participate in the development of short and long term goals, strategies and objectives for department efficiencies and enhanced cost containment programs along with operating procedures to ensure effective departmental performance monitoring and control
- •Maintain current knowledge and compliance with all applicable regulatory and accreditation standards
- •Comply with HIPAA, Diversity Principles, Corporate Integrity, compliance Program policies and other applicable corporate and departmental policies
- •Maintain communication with management regarding development within areas of assigned responsibilities and perform special projects as required or requested

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Illinois

5 years 5 months

Senior Supervisor

November 2013 - January 2014 (3 months)

Chicago, Illinois

Supervised the Disease Management nurses. Responsible for daily audits of nurses.

Registered Nurse

September 2008 - November 2013 (5 years 3 months)

Education

Indiana Wesleyan University

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Applied Management and Health Care Management · (2010 - 2012)

Governors State University

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Criminal Justice and Corrections · (2006 - 2008)